<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ty Keating</title>
    <description>Live Well and Treat Others Well</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 23:22:01 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 23:22:01 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Resume</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;font-size: 24px; font-weight: bold; text-align: center;&quot;&gt; Developer Based Experience &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 16px; font-weight: bold; list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;E2 ManageTech&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 12px;&quot;&gt;Technical Analyst&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 12px;&quot;&gt;January 2015 - Present&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Technical Analyst I work with as both a hands on dev and consultant. Our clients are leaders of Environmental Health and Safety Management for large scale organizations who are seeking software based solutions within their practice. I meet with our clients to gain context on their needs and then personally customize and configure proprietary software suites to help accomplish these goals. The custom expansions require adding, modifying, and creating new features within a private framework using functional programming principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The diversity of my project experience includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Incident Management Handling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Action Plans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foreign Data Integrations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Custom Report Building&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Metrics Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my time at E2 I have succeed in working with a private programming language with little documentation. This required a lot of late nights, constant research, and communicating with our senior devs to grow my knowledge base. I am now trusted and able to work on my and personally manage an account for a fortune 200 client. My most recent success was writing a data integration script that played a large role winning our company a 500 million dollar 5 year contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 16px; font-weight: bold; list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;Market Track&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 12px;&quot;&gt;Consultant&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 12px;&quot;&gt;November 2014 - December 2014&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cutting my teeth with paid dev work started at Market Track. Here I worked with a perl based software package writing web scraping software using regular expressions. My duties included digging into commerce site source code, isolating relevant tags, writing greedy capture expressions, and feeding the captures into the in-house software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having never worked with perl and very little experience with regex I had to learn quickly.  This was a 3 month contract and the team required instant results.  My first shift was a working interview where I was given the task of parsing through several regex puzzles provided by the senior devs. I skipped lunch and worked 10 hours straight to learn the commands and how to best capture the desired texts. At the end of the day my review was satisfactory and I was awarded the contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 16px; font-weight: bold; list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;Dev Bootcamp&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 12px;&quot;&gt;Developer Student&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 12px;&quot;&gt;May 2014 - July 2014&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The immersive 1000 hours of coding over 3 months program for aspiring devs. Here I built on the fundaments. I finished coding challenges using object oriented design methods, created applications in Sinatra and Rails, and built an iOS application over 8 days with a small group for final presentations. This space is no joke and it pushes all of your limits. I have acquired life long friends and colleagues in this program and think of it as one of the best decisions I have ever made for my future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;font-size: 24px; font-weight: bold; text-align: center;&quot;&gt; Pro Bono &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 16px; font-weight: bold; list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;Girl Develope It&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 12px;&quot;&gt;TA&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 12px;&quot;&gt;August 2014 - Present&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy spending my time giving back to the community. I volunteer as often as possible at GDI Chicago and have even had a little paid work from the organization for taking attendance and helping with set-up when the organizers have scheduling conflicts. I have some strong friendships with many of the awesome women that make these classes great and I often learn while I help teach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 16px; font-weight: bold; list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;Rails Bridge Chicago&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 12px;&quot;&gt;TA&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 12px;&quot;&gt;November 2014 - Present&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great organization providing women and eager beginners a safe place to dive into coding.  I participate in the larger meet ups where a private organization opens their space to bring in 90+ aspiring devs to work through all day coding challenges at their own pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 16px; font-weight: bold; list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;Common Cause Illinois&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 12px;&quot;&gt;Volunteer Campaign Site Build&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 12px;&quot;&gt;October 2014 - November 2015&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an undergrad in Policy Analysis I put the majority of my time into research projects involving the Net Neutrality landscape. I met some organizers at a drink up downtown Chicago and jumped at the chance to build a site to help build awareness of this paramount issue involving our freedom and usage of the resource that keeps us connected and secures our livelihood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project is built on a rails framework holding a single model of constituents and their statements. The styling is custom out of the box SASS.  I tied my own bootlaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chicagofornetneutrality.com/&quot;&gt;Chicago for Net Neutrality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;font-size: 24px; font-weight: bold; text-align: center;&quot;&gt; Other Flavors &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 16px; font-weight: bold; list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;Big Sky Youth Empowerment&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 12px;&quot;&gt;Volunteer Mentor&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 12px;&quot;&gt;November 2009 - August 2012&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Montana based organization that provides high risk youth with an alternative concept of risk management. It was a blast. I was able to help high schoolers problem solve and build confidence through outdoor activities. Every Sunday we would do out door adventures. In the winter I taught skiing and snowboarding. In the summer we did whitewater rafting, hiking, and climbing! On Wednesdays I would participate in team building workshops checkins and some light tutoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 16px; font-weight: bold; list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;Copper Whiskey Bar&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 12px;&quot;&gt;Cook&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 12px;&quot;&gt;April 2011 - September 2011&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before going deciding to become I software developer I was saving to go to culinary school. This was the last restaurant I worked at and by far the most rewarding. I was involved in the opening of the business and received a wide array of fine arts training in a French kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is relevant because it was what sent me down the path of software development. I was working 80 hour weeks immersing myself in this craft. All the while I would day dream about how I would grow to improve the restaurant I would eventually own and operate. My obsessive thinking lead me to the restaurant point of sales system(POS) and how I would make a better. As time past I found myself doing more dev work and less home cooking. That is where it all began!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 16:05:45 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/jekyll/update/resume</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/jekyll/update/resume</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory - edit this post and re-build (or run with the &lt;code&gt;-w&lt;/code&gt; switch) to see your changes!
To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention: YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Tom&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &amp;#39;Hi, Tom&amp;#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 09:44:21 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/jekyll/update/welcome-to-jekyll</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/jekyll/update/welcome-to-jekyll</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
