<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ty Keating</title>
    <description>Live Well and Treat Others Well</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 00:36:37 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 00:36:37 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Working on My Time</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On November 8th, 2013 I left my home, friends, and family to find myself. The significance of taking that first step is still very unclear.  What I do know is that I set in motion a barrage of life changes. These changes came on so quickly that I am only now able to begin decompressing all of the mental stock that has been collected and stored during this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of my exit it was a calculated risk. I was cook, ski bum, and recent undergrad. I was full of a growing discontent of the notion that I was on the verge of becoming townie. There is nothing wrong with staying one place if you are happy. I had many hobbies and gave back to the community. I had a tendency to overindulge in my vices from time to time, but progress was being made to shrug off things that were once a necessity to a young man. I was a DJ of a late night radio show on campus and sponsored by a hiking shoe company. The year I left I helped open 2 local restaurants in the heart of downtown. On most accounts I was not failing at life. I only knew that not leaving, that not taking this chance, would result in one burning question. What else is out there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a lot to say about my past and even more to speculate about my future. I fully intend to take some time to get these thoughts on the page in coming months. The above is the background. The below is what happens to be on mind this evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a wise ass long haired 18 year old college freshman. It was early fall and I was fully enjoying the nights that never seemed to end. Attending college in Bozeman Montana (roughly 150 miles from my hometown) provided me with a rush freedom that I had never felt. The absence of any kind of tangible accountability filled me with excitement and suspense. As an inherently independent person, I had every intention of gulping down each ounce of this new found privilege. It was a self constructed reality; but in my mind, my cup runneth over. The true impotence of my decisions came to me years later as I struggled to deconstruct each intentionally laid brick of my ignorance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come down to the office and lets have a chat”, he said. It was Sunday morning and I was 45 minutes late for work. I was on prep duty at local pizza shop that was proud of its quirky pies, farm to table products, and ‘work hard, play harder’ mission statement. My boss (and one of the assistant managers) was the reasonable type; the kind of fella you might imagine to be overseeing the college kids and snowboard washouts that populated the ranks of this establishment. I think he bought me a bottle of gin the night before. He lead me to the downstairs office which was littered with paperwork and fishing flies. I was about to get the famous ‘come to Jesus’ speech that folks on verge of getting the boot hear. It is generally a mix of leading questions about your your current happiness in the position and what the company can do to improve your moral. As an experienced duck diver in the face of trouble I prepared myself to apologize profusely take responsibility for everything. I would then express how I would die in the trenches if given the chance to slice onions and lob mozz for a little longer. Then he hit me with a curve ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is a very important and exciting time in your life. I encourage you to analyze your surroundings and take in your priorities. If I could go back to college at your age and do it all again I would be there in heart beat. There are a lot of things that you are trying do and a lot of types of people you are trying to be. If you need the time to figure those things out, I whole heartedly encourage you to take that time. The catch is… That time is your time. Its not my time and I cannot afford to have your time interfering with my time. The choice is yours. Now get up there and get to work. Or don’t. I would just appreciate you giving me the proper notice if that is the case.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew when I heard this that it was something very important. A once in a lifetime moment delivered with just the right amount of brevity. I didn’t understand it then but it has stuck with me for years. I still think about it all the time. It drives my work ethic and how I handle my commitments. Within the walls of dirty little pizza place magic can happen. Never estimate an individual and take stock of your time. Make every second count.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 18:19:21 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/on_my_time</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/on_my_time</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Net Neutrality Policy Landscape</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an attempt at delivering a concise explanation to a very complicated policy landscape.  I have written on and studied Net Neutrality, on a policy level, since 2010 and will happily answer any questions with as little bias as possible.  Regardless of alignment, Net Neutrality is very important and complex.  The nature of both the policy and how it is being presented publicly has a lot to do with why such an important issue is largely misunderstood or overlooked.  Please email (via footer links) if you would like me to clarify or provide more in-depth information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-net-neutrality&quot;&gt;What is Net Neutrality?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Net Neutrality is the term coined for the debate between public and private sector policy players in regards to the how broadband providers are allowed to control and distribute our nation’s internet connections. More specifically, the government organization, the FCC, is trying to decide what type of policy they should have in regards to these distributions.  As of now, the government has no Constitutional permissions to make any choices in regards to broadband commercial distributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;if-the-fcc-decides-to-keep-the-hands-off-policy&quot;&gt;If the FCC decides to keep the hands off policy…&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without government regulation network providers can decide how they choose the pricing for network distributions.  More importantly providers can regulate the speed of connections for both the user and the content available on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-this-should-be-thought-about&quot;&gt;Why this should be thought about&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Often only a single distribution company occupies an entire region.  This is a monopoly. The government has laws in place to protect price gouging from other natural monopolies like power companies.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Companies like Comcast/NBCU are a conglomerate of both a major network distributions company and a major content provider. This means the same company making money distributing internet connections also has a personal financial stake in content that can be viewed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Currently, network providers are trying to impose tiered service offerings for content.  This means a web-based company could pay additional fees to make their content show up faster and in more searches.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is no indication that providing faster speeds and tiered services, for content, is a matter of resource management.  This means that companies paying for a faster service will actually be paying not to be slowed down.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/share&quot; class=&quot;twitter-share-button&quot; data-url=&quot;http://bontgoy.github.io/open-internet/&quot; data-text=&quot;A brief explanation of Net Neutrality&quot; data-via=&quot;Bontgoy&quot;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;script&gt;!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?&#39;http&#39;:&#39;https&#39;;if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+&#39;://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#39;;fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, &#39;script&#39;, &#39;twitter-wjs&#39;);&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2014 08:44:21 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/net_neutrality</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/net_neutrality</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Letter to Zed</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This letter was written to Zed A Shaw in response to his post &lt;a href=&quot;http://zedshaw.com/2014/10/19/the-coming-code-bootcamp-destruction/&quot;&gt;The Coming Code Bootcamp Destruction&lt;/a&gt;.  I fixed some grammar by adding a few words like “that” and “is” that I left out in the throws of passion for improved readabilty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi zedshaw,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you have been getting a flood of emails and feedback for your upcoming posts about bootcamp destruction.  Im excited to read what you have to say.  I am a graduate of Dev Bootcamp Chicago.  I would love to tell you my story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to to try and bear the best of me so that you can understand why the worst of me chose to attend Dev Bootcamp.  I work hard.  I work really hard.  I put myself through college working two jobs and spending weekends volunteering at a local non-profit.  My political science degree was a poor choice based on my aptitude but a great choice based on my need to multitask.  I often appear as a student who comes in at the middle and finishes just above the bottom.  At least in my mind I do.  I passed college without finishing a single text book; literally.  That is not a point of pride.  When I can focus things go really well but I need a thing to do with both hands or I find myself day dreaming about white noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After college I spent about a year job hunting while paying my bills as a waiter and cook.  Along the way the glamor of volunteer letter writing for campaigns lost its luster.  As a 12 year restaurant industry vet I decided that I should save up and go to culinary school.  During that time I spent 80 hours a week working in restaurants fully immersing my mind and body into the trade.  I began coming up with ideas to improve the imaginary restaurant I would undoubtedly own and operate.  Most of my unique solutions where ones that involved usage and placement of Point of Sales systems.  I have ideas to improve an industry I have deep experience in and at the time had no means to produce a result.  For word space sake this part of the story leads me to taking my culinary school savings and investing in Dev Bootcamp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I struggled along the way.  I pulled knowledge from both Learn Ruby the Hard Way and Learn Coding the Hard way.  I also read Learn to Program by Chris Pine and Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby by Sandi Metz.  I read those books cover to cover; something I have never done before.  I drew from The Well-Grounded Rubyist, The RSPEC Book, and Understanding the Four Rules of Simple Design.  I read Learn to Count and am working through The Big Nerd Ranch: Objective C Programming book.  I finished DBC Chicago three months ago and I have been diligently job hunting this entire time.  I have not found work and I am not afraid.  I hope I do not come across as someone who just jumps into a snake oil project because of a shiny carrot.  I didn’t leave a career because I hated it or wanted to make more money.  I want to contribute where I know I can contribute.  I was going to drop 70K on cooking school to likely make 12 dollars an hour for the first 3 years and after that barely 40K a year.  I have thought out my path and I will suffer properly until I get where I need to be on my own terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not alone.  My lived experiences may be unique but the types of folks I have met at DBC often hold a very deliberate reason to attend and it has less to do with pie eyed dreams of living the easy life.  I love that you want to hold organizations accountable for their methods and misconduct.  I feel very strongly about integrity.  My letter to you is to give you an honest account of a very particular demographic of individuals that take their choices very seriously.  Things that I did and learned at Dev Bootcamp were what I needed in order to get me to where I am now which is jobless and skilled enough to take one more step forward in the mud.  I did my research and at no point came into the program with any misconceptions; and in turn, it provided what I expected and more.  I made friends that are likeminded and unflappable.  Please give feedback that is Actionable, Specific, and Kind.  Ill be fine either way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tyler Keating&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 16:05:45 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/zed_letter</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/zed_letter</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
